# Richard A Careaga

System Administrator and Consultant
"Only He Who Can See The Invisible Can Do The Impossible" Frank Gaines

#### Cover Letter

#### To whom it concerns:

As you will see, I especially excel in the areas of computer technology and electronics, skills which I honed through my years of working with both the private and military sectors, along with my own enjoyment of electronic devices and the electrical arts. During my career, I have become especially gifted in diagnosing, repairing and performing maintenance on various types of both consumer and military electronics. Aside from my sound technical skills, and military experience, I have over 15 years of recent work experience in the private sector, thus giving me a real-world, hands-on view on the importance of professionalism, attention to detail, and possibly most crucial, customer satisfaction. In both my work and in my life I value the importance of teamwork and functioning at a high level, even in sometimes stressful situations, and I am looking forward to applying my skills and unique personality to this new job.

I look forward to setting up an interview and sharing more about my work and skills.

Respectfully,

Richard Careaga

#### PRIMARY AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- 1. OS X Server (9 10)
- 2.Windows Server (6 10)
- 3. Linux Server (7 10)
- 4. Coding (8 10)
- 5. Security (8 10)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Marquez Charter School
Pacific Palisades, LAUSD "Contractor"
Apr 2015 — Sep 2016 (1 yr, 6s mos)
System Administrator and Consultant.

Duties: This position's primary responsibility were to coordinate and provide technical support for Marquez Charter School staff and faculty including management and oversight of the Digital Edge technology program. Apple OS X; MacBook Air and MacBook Pro model, Apple iOS; iPads, iPod Touch, etc. (2)Google Apps (Gmail; Google Docs; etc.)(3)Google Chrome OS (Chromebooks). (4) Windows XP, Vista, and 7 workstations (Dell, HP, Lenovo)(5) Microsoft Office suite on both Mac and Windows(6)SonicWall Firewalls and/or other Content Filtering Services(7) Classroom technology SMART Boards, document cameras, projectors)(8) Working knowledge of LAN and WAN network fundamentals and protocols.

## A.S.E. ENRICHMENT Inc

# Computer Teacher

— Apr 2015 ( 9 mos)

Duties: Instructor of a computer programming course (Java) for children 8-12 years. Develop lesson plans to ensure educational goals are met and schedules are maintained. Develop constructive solutions to assist students with unique learning styles. Team-approach to learning to implement other faculty members and parents.

#### **TOPAZ**

**Technical Support** 

Jan 2015 — Mar 2015 (9 mos)

Duties: Troubleshooting various software and hardware errors relating to state-of-the-art signature-capturing pads. Tested and diagnosed with defective and broken equipment. Provided technical support to clients and assisted in the procurement of new clients by answering technical questions during sales bids. Using company software to maintain detailed logs and spreadsheets.

Gainsaver; Long Beach,

Equipment Refurbishing Technician

Jan 2014 — Aug 2014 (1 yr, 4 mos)

Duties: Diagnosing and repairing of various Macintosh devices; refurbish company electrical dispensing equipment. Performing operational checks and sanitation required for electrical equipment. Accountable for the inventory of over tenuousness refurbished Macintosh computers and devices. Implementing new categorizing systems for the warehouse and its inventory.

### A Careaga Plumbing

Plumber / Maintenance

Jan 2011 — Aug 2013 (2 yrs, 8 mos)

Duties: Re-piping in a cleanroom environment. Measuring, cutting, threading, and bending pipes to required angles, using hand and power tools or machines such as pipe cutters, pipe-threading machines, and pipe-bending machine, while in a cleanroom. Preparing project cost estimates and procuring materials.

**United States Navy** 

# Third Class Petty Officer USN

Nov 2007 — Nov 2011 (4 yrs, 1 mo)

Duties: Electronic device/system installation/repair, electronic equipment calibration and maintenance of Naval Air Cushion Landing Crafts. Instrumental in devising safety guidelines used to conduct proper craft maintenance. Became skilled with metalworking tools various heavy power tools. Worked as a network IT specialist, maintaining servers, securing military networks, handling classified information and materials security. Firearm and explosives handling.

#### **EDUCATION**

California State University Northridge BS, Computer Engineering In Progress Golden West College AA, Liberal Arts

## References

#### Gillian Keller

Teacher at LAUSD

Richard is very talented and up to date on all technological issues. He was able to fix problems for me in a very short amount of time compared to his predecessor who couldn't fix it in a year. He was reliable, flexible, and always ready to come by and fix urgent issues. He will be an asset to any company or job he applies for in the future.

#### Christina Baello

Administrative Assistant at University of Michigan Healthcare System

I have known Richard for many years as a reliable friend. He is a hard-working driven individual and always strives to create innovative solutions to everyday problems. A great addition to any team.

#### **Garrett Jeannette**

IT Support Specialist at Commerce casino

I have known Richard for over 25 years. I am an IT Support Specialist and had pretty much learned everything I know from Richard. He would 100% make a new employer worthwhile and always tries to go above and beyond no matter what the task is.

## **Dustin Miller**

Business Director at MVRK Engineers

I've known Richard for approximately 15 years. The first time I saw his skill in action, he tore apart the panel on my Toyota Tacoma to solder a loose wire. When my car was in pieces, I was pretty skeptical that there would be a successful outcome, however, Richard impressed me with his technical knowledge and viola, my stereo was fixed! Throughout the years Richard has been one of my go-to's for computer, internet, and other technical or mechanical issues that required his technical expertise.